无赖！
Scoundrel!
你应该提前告诉我们的
You should have atleast told us.
告诉你什么？
Told you what?
祝你生日快乐，瓦伊巴夫
Best wishes on your birthday, Vaibhav.
我永远不会忘记我们第一次见面的情景
I will never forget the first time we met.
你站在走廊里又饿又渴，而我..
You were standing there hungry and thirsty in the corridor and I..
-不是…… -听我说完
It's not.. - Let me complete.
第一眼看到你，我就觉得我在前往计算机科学的旅程中
At first sight I felt I'd found my companion..
找到了同伴
..on the journey to IT Bombay Computer science.
米纳，今天不是我的生日
Meena, it is not my birthday.
你们有钱人随时都可以吃蛋糕吗？
Do you rich people eat cake whenever you want?
我去马赫什瓦里看了瓦蒂卡的考试成绩
I went to Maheshwari to check on Vartika's results.
路上碰到一家蛋糕店，所以我就买了一个蛋糕
I came across a bakery on the way so, I bought a cake.
如果我告诉她这个好消息，她会很高兴的
She would be happy when I'd tell her the good news.
她会称赞我，让我觉得自己是个英雄
She would give me credit. I will feel like a hero.
然后你就可以亲她了
And you will get to kiss her.
对吧，兄弟? 一定是这样，然后呢？
Right, bro? You were right. Then?
然后……我看到成绩了
What then? I saw the results.
瓦蒂卡没考过，我过了
Vartika didn't make it. I did.
你仔细看成绩单了吗？
Did you check the results thoroughly?
我从上到下看了八遍
Eight times. From up to down.
你教了她那么多，但她还是没通过？
You taught her so much, bro, and yet she didn't make it?
她可真笨
She's a very dumb girl..
不过很适合做女朋友
..but good choice for girlfriend.
不，很多同学都参加了考试
No. Many students sat for the exam. Somesh. Shubham.
阿洛克，尤察夫，他们的名字都在名单上
Alok. Utsav. All their names were on the list.
-我们班的尤察夫?-是的
Our Shubham? - Yes.
马赫什瓦里这批只招80人
Maheshwari has batches of 80 students.
如果招200人，那瓦蒂卡才能通过
If they had batches of 200 students then Vartika would have made it.
你在哪个组?-A3
Which batch did you get? - A3.
太好了! 如果老师都没能进入第一组
Great! When the teacher didn't make it to the first batch..
他怎么能指望他的学生进去呢？
..how can he expect his student to get selected?
你就像巴特拉
You are just like Batla.
-嘿! 就连布吉扬都能考到A3了 -天啊！
Hey! Even Abhigyan made it in A3. - Oh!
那边的A3级学生有80%的可能性
The A3 students in over there have 80 percent probability..
考上印度理工
..of getting selected to JEE.
我不是故意参加考试的
I didn't mean to sit for the exam.
有什么问题吗？
What is the problem?
她没通过也许是件好事
It's a good thing she did not make it.
怎么个好法？
How is it good?
怎么会好呢? 她坐在房间里一定很伤心
How is it good? She must be very sad, sitting in room.
看到她难过，我会感到很难过
It will make me feel very bad to see her sad.
别管什么英雄时刻了，我没有勇气去看她
Never mind the hero moment, I don't have the nerve to go see her.
你已经进入了 A1，但是你仍然保持着 A10的心态
You have made it to A1 but you have the same old A10 mentality.
有点远见，不要总想着现在
Be a little foresighted. Don't think about the present.
想想未来
Think about the future.
听着，如果她通过了，她就会去维吉安纳加尔
Look, if she had made it, she would have gone to Vigyan Nagar.
而你被困在这里
You would be stuck in Talwandi.
你们每天要怎么见面？
How would you meet on a daily basis?
你来科塔已经四个月了，对吧？
It's been four months since you came to Kota, right?
你去过几次维吉安纳加尔？
How many times have you been to Vidyanagar?
我们可以折中的地点见面
We could meet midway somewhere.
当然，你每次都能去，但她又能来几次
Sure, you would go. She wouldn't come time and again.
你很幸运
You were lucky.
看，现在你可以练习化学了
Look, now you can practice chemistry..
在这里悠闲地度过一年
..in the streets of Talwandi at leisure through the year.
赢得她的芳心
Win her heart.
然后，你们就能像乌代所说的那样了
Then if you wish you can do what Uday said as well.
该死！
Crap!
米纳，你越来越聪明了
Meena, you have become very smart.
当然，我可不是无缘无故进入 A1的
Of course. I'm not in A1 without reason.
太棒了！
Wonderful!
怎么样，兄弟们？
What do you say, brothers?
可以吃蛋糕了吗?-好的，当然
Shall we have cake? - Yes, yes. Of course.
-我已经七年没吃蛋糕了-吃吧
It has been seven years since I had cake. - Eat.
教务处打来的电话
It's a call from the coaching class.
又没到缴费的时间，他们为什么现在打电话来？
We still have time to pay the fees. Why are they calling now?
你好
Hello.
什么?-什么？
What? - What?
我还以为你在难过-不，我没事
I thought you'd be mourning. - No. I'm okay.
是的，当我看到面包和果酱的时候我就知道了
Yes, I could tell when I saw the bread and jam.
但是，怎么这么冷静？
But so chill?
你很放松，因为你的英雄通过了，对吗？
You are relaxed because your hero made it, right?
听着，我为他感到高兴，但他不是英雄
Listen. I'm happy for him that he made it but he's no hero.
我真搞不懂你们
I've never understood you girls till date.
如果你喜欢这个男孩，那就去跟他表白啊
If you like the boy, then go and propose to him.
就不，我们先偷偷地搞暧昧，然后等他来表白
No. First we will romance secretly. Then we wait for him to propose.
然后我再考虑答不答应
Following which we shall think whether to say yes or no.
等一下，我为什么要表白？
Just a minute. Why should I propose?
你喜欢那个男孩?-你又开始那样了
You like the boy? - You're back to that again.
去把这个交给瓦伊巴夫
Go and give this lecture to Vaibhav.
时代变了，姐妹，你喜欢的那种男人
Those times are gone, madam The kind of guy you like..
在你的情况下，你要向他表白并且亲吻他
..in your case you will have to propose and initiate the first kiss as well.
-说得好像你会跟乌代表白似的?-我会的，我觉得没问题
Like you proposed to Uday? - I would. I see no problem in it..
但我不需要，乌代可不是胆小鬼
..but I didn't need to. He isn't that pussy.
好吧，如果他是个胆小鬼，那就随他去吧
Alright. If he is such a pussy then let it be.
你怀疑吗? 不要怀疑了
You are in doubt? Don't remain doubtful.
他会答应的，他对你非常感兴趣
He will say yes. He's highly interested.
乌代告诉你了？
Uday told you?
姐妹，你觉得为什么《复活节快乐》这么受欢迎？
Madam, why do you think Shivangi Renawat is so popular in 'Paschim Vihar"?
因为她能嗅到浪漫的气息
Because she can sniff romance.
而且乌代也告诉了我
And Uday told me as well.
听着，如果你愿意，你可以采纳我的建议，但我没有强迫你
Look, you take my advice if you wish but there is no compulsion.
等等，乌代跟你说了什么？
Listen. What did Uday say to you?
先生，我们没有什么特别的理由去参加考试
Sir, we didn't have any particular reason to sit for the exams.
六个小时，第一卷，第二卷，一共240道题
Six hours. Paper one. Paper two. 240 questions.
还说没什么特别的理由？
All of you sat for them for no particular reason?
真不错！
Bravo!
是的，先生，我也没有特别的理由
Yes, sir. Even I had no particular reason for it.
我们将与参加马赫什瓦里考试的同一批学生在JEE考试中竞争
We will be competing in JEE with the same students who sit for Maheshwari's test.
知己知彼，百战不殆
Sir, one should know who one is competing with.
-这就是我去参加考试的原因 -俺也一样
That's why I sat for it. - Yes, that is the correct reason.
我的意思是，这也是我的理由，先生
I mean to say that is my reason too, sir.
我也没有其他特殊的原因
Even I sat for it without reason, sir.
你也是？
You too?
先生，他是故意去考的，他还提前30分钟到达考场
Sir, he was deliberate. He reached there 30 minutes early.
而且他不是一个人去的，他还带他妹妹参加了考试
And he did not go alone. He even got his sister to sit for the exam.
她不是我妹妹
She is not my sister.
你在想什么，瓦伊巴夫·潘迪？
What were you thinking, Vaibhav Pandey?
我们优秀的学生都去参加了马赫什瓦里的入学考试
Our top students will go to sit for Maheshwari's entrance test..
而我们却不知道？
..and we wouldn't know?
你到底有什么问题？
What is your problem anyway?
为什么不跟我说
You don't talk to me.
你们都是真正的天才
All of you are the real prodigies .
我们所有人都支持你
All of us are here for you.
我之前也说过，只有A1组的学生都是我的强盗
I've said this earlier as well. A1 students are my rankers.
其他的学生都是我的提款机
The rest are my bankers.
我根本不在乎他们
I don't care about them.
告诉我，舒伯汉，你有什么问题吗？
Tell me, Shubham. What problem do you have here?
阿洛克？
Alok?
瓦伊巴夫？
Vaibhav?
神童的课程有什么问题？
What is so wrong at Prodigy classes?
你们有什么建议吗？
Do you guys have any suggestions?
真的没问题吗？
You have no problem?
好吧，那你们告诉我那边有什么好的
Alright. Tell me what's good over there.
有吗？
What is better over there?
听着，无论你在这还是在那边，都能考上
Look. You will be selected either here or there.
但在这里，你们将成为最佳人选
But here you will be toppers.
还会得到一份奖品
You will receive a prize.
我们甚至为前十名支付了印度理工的学费
We even pay the IIT fees of the top ten rankers here.
我们做的市场营销比他们多得多
We do far more marketing than them.
看看他
Look at him.
里茹·加那
Rijul Jain.
他的全印度排名是19
His All India Rank was 19.
我们把这张脸贴满了全城
We plastered his face all over the city.
给了他一辆宝马
We gave him a BMW.
把他捧成了明星
We made him a star.
明星！
Star.
他18岁时收到了四份求婚书
He received four proposals at the age of 18.
这些都不能吸引你们吗？
Is that a small feat?
他们会打印这么大的照片吗？
Will they print such big photos?
他们只会印一个小的
They will print a tiny one.
听着，孩子们，如果你们现在换培训班，你们的日常生活就会受到影响
Look, boys. If you shift there now, your routine will suffer.
另外，他们只会专注于从11年级
Plus they will focus on their toppers..
就入学的顶尖的学生
..who have been with them since the 11th grade.
我知道索梅什的弱点是S块
Over here I know that Somesh is weak with S block.
瓦伊巴夫的平衡学的不好
Vaibhav's Equilibrium is haywire.
所以我会给你们补课
So I'll take extra classes.
给你们留作业
I'll give them practice question papers.
我会解决你们的疑惑
I will solve their doubts.
你们会在那边能有这样的待遇吗? 告诉我
Are you going to receive such personal care over there? Tell me.
-能吗?-不能，先生
Will you? - Yes, sir.
我明白，我不去
I understand. I won't go.
如果你们还有任何疑问的话，现在告诉我？
Ask me now if you have any doubts?
告诉我
Tell me.
大家都确定吗?-是的，先生！
Is everyone sure? - Yes, sir!
我是说，我也是，哦不，我也不是，我不去，先生
I mean, me too, sir. Me neither, sir. Not going, sir.
你们付了12年级的学费吗？
Did you pay the fees for 12th grade?
-还没有，但我们会付的 -先生，我爸爸会付款的
No, sir. I have to. - Sir, dad will do so.
我们会付钱的，先生
It will be paid, sir.
We'll pay it, sir.
如果你还没有付款，也没关系，如果你已经付了，不用担心
If haven't paid, it is okay and if you have paid it, don't worry.
我们会退款的
We will refund it.
A1组额外提供20% 奖学金
20 percent extra scholarships for the A1 batch.
如果你去那儿，你就得付更高的费用
If you go there you will have to pay higher fees..
而留在这里我们给你发奖学金
..whereas we are giving you scholarships over here.
好吗？
Okay?
好吧，把小册子给他们
Fine. Give them the booklets.
还有我的电话号码也给他们
Give all of them my number too.
我的个人号码
My personal number.
还有问题吗？
Okay?
好吧，解散
Well, alright. Dismiss.
- 谢谢，先生-谢谢，先生
Thank you, sir. - Thank you, sir.
对不起，先生
Sorry, sir.
你有他们所有人的名单，是吗？
You have a list of all their names, don't you?
打电话给他们的父母
Call their parents.
我们帮助他们通过 NTSE，KVPY 和奥林匹克
We help them get through NTSE, KVPY and Olympiad..
然而这些白眼狼却把他们的排名交给马赫什瓦里
..and the scoundrels will give their ranks to Maheshwari.
不用这么紧张，先生
You are tense without reason, sir.
我跟他们谈过了，他们哪儿也不会去
I've spoken to them. They won't go anywhere.
巴特拉先生，在培训行业，这一年至关重要
Mr. Batla, in the coaching business it's all about one year only.
如果他们今年没有拿到排名，我们明年就得不到入学许可了
If they don't get a rank this year we won't get admissions next year.
我们还要把他的照片挂多久？
How long will we print his photo anyway?
他看起来好丑
He looks so ugly.
是的，先生，真丑
Yes, sir. That is true.
但是，先生，如果你找一个孩子们都尊重的人去跟他们谈
But, sir, when a respected man talks to the children..
-那他们一定会听的-确实
..theydefinitely pay heed to him. -Correct.
叫杰图先生和他们谈谈，他们会听话的
Call Jeetu sir to talk to them. They will pay heed to him.
-他用了你的名字?-不仅如此
He took your name? - Not just my name.
他给了我这张卡片，上面有他的个人号码
He gave me this card with his personal number.
-他还给了我奖学金-给我看看
He even gave me scholarship. - Show me.
好好学习，否则你不会得到它
Work hard. You don't get it otherwise.
我打赌迪帕克看到这些尖子生要跳槽一定紧张的不行
I bet Deepak must have been sweating bullets seeing the toppers run.
是的，他对我们说话很有礼貌
Yes. He talked to us so politely...
我爸爸都没跟我说话这么客气过
My dad never spoke to me so politely.
巴特拉是个感性的人
And Batla was so sentimental ..
他一定会升职的
He will surely get a promotion.
他说现在你在 A1，一切都会顺利的
He said now that you are in A1 now it will be smooth sailing.
我们误解了巴特拉
We have misunderstood Batla.
他甚至知道我的弱项
He even knows that I am weak at equilibrium.
他说会给我额外补课
He said I shall give you extra classes.
放弃马赫什瓦里，并留在神童的学生都赢得了尊重
Students who leave Maheshwari and remain with Prodigy gain respect.
我去年也放弃了马赫什瓦里，但是我没有得到任何回报
I too left Maheshwari last year but I didn't gain any.
我应该重新参加考试吗? 下一次考试是什么时候？
Shall I reappear for the exams? When is the next exam?
现在有什么好处，伙计？
What good will it do now, buddy?
优等生都已经考完了
The toppers already sat for the exam.
没错，反正他们也要开始新学期了
That's right. Their batches are going to begin anyway.
你可以明年参加
You can appear for it next year.
但是没有人会真的过去
But nobody is going to go.
为什么?-他们参加考试都只是为了了解竞争情况
Why? - All of them sat for the exam only to check out the competition.
我们那么努力才进入到A1组，为什么现在要走？
We worked so hard to get to A1. Why would they go now?
是的，没错
Yes, that is correct.
嘿！索梅什
Hey, Somesh.
舒巴姆，我们在一起学习已经一年了
Shubham, we have been studying together for the past one year.
你从没告诉过我你是比哈尔族人
You never told me you are a Bihari.
-不，我是来自格勒亨迪县的奥里亚族人 -我知道了
No, I am Oriya. From Kalahandi. - I see.
你的意思是你说话不像“我们正在做这件事”或“我们正在说那件事”
Do you mean you don't talk like "we are doing this" or "we are saying that?"
不是的
No.
那你他妈的为什么在那里乱说话？
Then why the fuck were you using those words over there?
我们之前就是这么定的呀
That's what we decided we would say.
你这头猪! 你应该说你不去的
You swine! You were supposed to say you aren't going.
但你说“我们” ，这不就说明我们已经串通好了吗？
If you say "We", won't he know we have formed a group?
天知道什么样的白痴会去马赫什瓦里
Lord knows what kind of idiots make it to Maheshwari.
甜点给我
Give me dessert.
下次有人问你，你就说你不去
Next time anyone asks you say you aren't going.
如果他问起其他人，你就说你不知道
If he asks about the others, you say you don't know.
我没跟任何人讨论过这件事
I haven't spoken to anyone about it.
否则他们所有人都会追着我们不放
Else all of them will hound us.
我觉得巴特拉的话很有道理
I felt what Batla said made sense.
别听他的，他在胡说八道！
Don't listen to him. He was talking nonsense!
你的S块很差，那是因为他教得不好
You are weak at S block because he didn't teach it well.
巴特拉嫉妒我们，他自己都想去马赫什瓦里
Batla is jealous of us. He wants to go to Maheshwari himself..
但是马赫什瓦里不雇佣非印度理工毕业的教师
..but Maheshwari does not employ non-IITian teachers.
我们已经到了A1组，不是吗？
We have made it to A1 somehow, haven't we?
-这不是也挺好的-在这里任何白痴都能进A1组
We will deal with it. - Any idiot can make it to A1 over here.
你去马赫什瓦里考个A1我看看
Try getting into the A1 batch at Maheshwari.
它被称为最好的学院不是没有道理的
It is not known as the best institute without reason.
这里的人JEE都考不好
These people cannot handle JEE.
而那边的学生正在一个接一个地破解奥林匹克竞赛题
Their students are cracking one Olympiad after another.
以后也是一样，他们会跟你打感情牌
In future too they will lay it on thick with their emotional crap.
别理他，知道为什么吗？
Don't pay heed. You know why?
因为这里有的，马赫什瓦里也有
Because they have several things at Maheshwari that are missing here..
因为这里没有的，马赫什瓦里也都有
..but they don't have anything over here that is missing at Maheshwari.
杰图·拜亚？
Jeetu Bhaiya?
我不去，拜亚哥
I am not going, Bhaiya.
我已经开始学静电学了
I have already started electrostatics.
那你为什么还参加考试
Then why did you sit for the exam.
没什么
No reason.
我想看看我到底什么水平
I wanted to see where I stand.
什么水平? 你到 A1了吗？
Did you see? Did you make it to A1?
我在 A3，但是我不去了，拜亚哥
I made it to A3. But I am not going, Bhaiya.
舒伯汉，你的朋友到底去不去？
Shubham, is your friend going or not?
拜亚哥，我不去，我也不知道他去不去
Bhaiya, I am not going. I don't know about him..
因为我们还没讨论过，我只能告诉你我的计划
..because we haven't discussed it. I can only tell you of my plans.
- 你们还没讨论过?-没有
You haven't discussed it? - No.
你们是朋友，朋友之间应该讨论一下的
You are friends. Friends should discuss things.
我们不是朋友，他都不知道我是奥里亚族
We aren't friends, Bhaiya. He doesn't even know I am Oriya.
- 你来自格勒亨迪县，对吗?-是的，但我不去
From Kalahandi, right? - Yes. But I am not going.
没错，拜亚哥，我们也不去了
That's right, Bhaiya. Even we are not going.
好吧，那就没什么好说的了
Well, alright. There's no point then.
你们都走吧
All of you go. Chill.
拜亚哥
Bhaiya.
我听到他们在餐厅里聊天了
I heard both Shubham and Alok talking in the mess.
他们两个都要去马赫什瓦里
Both of them are going to Maheshwari.
我可以给你书面保证-我知道，这种事每年都会发生
I'd give you that in writing. - I know. It happens every year.
我也知道你不会去，但事实上你应该去
I also know that you aren't going, when in fact you should go.
每年我们这里都有像你这样的人
Every year we even have someone like you over here.
别说笑了，拜亚哥
Please stop ragging me, Bhaiya.
我是因为瓦蒂卡才去考试的
I only sat for the exam because Vartika..
我以后再跟你解释，但是我不想去
I'll tell you later. But I don't want to go.
你去考试是件好事
You did a good thing by sitting for it.
既然你已经通过了，那你就应该去
Now that you have been selected you should go.
你可以好好学学物理学
Look, you can manage physics.
你的化学和数学都有待提高
You have a problem with chemistry and Math.
既然你已经放弃了化学
Now that you are giving up inorganic..
那就要加强数学和物理，不是吗？
..you have to strengthen organic and physical, right?
那边的老师教得更好
It is taught well over there.
但是我现在已经在这里稳定下来了
But I am settled over here now, Bhaiya.
一切都很顺利
Everything is going well.
我为什么要现在离开？
Why would I leave now?
如果你不去，你要怎么提升自己?
How will you grow if you don't go? Tell me.
俗话说得好，如果你是班上最聪明的人
You know the saying, if you're the smartest person in the class..
那你就进错班了
..you're in the wrong class.
你在这里和谁竞争？
With whom will you compete over here?
你所有的竞争对手都离开了
All your competition will leave.
舒伯汉姆和阿洛克，你们组的人都会离开的
Your batches, Shubham and Alok. All of them will leave.
与其在这里得意洋洋地呆在 A1
Rather than getting complacent in A1 over here..
还不如在那边的A3挣扎
..you'll be better off struggling in A3 over there.
考到那边的 A1去
Make your way to A1 over there.
但是你在这里，拜亚哥
But you are over here, Bhaiya.
你一次能爱上多少人？
How many people are you going to fall in love with at one time?
你不明白
You don't understand.
如果你想成长，你必须继续前进
You must continue to move if you wish to grow.
如果你想听我的讲座，我每周都会上传非学院的课程
If you want my lecture I give them on Unacademy plus every week.
你看重播就好了
Watch the live lecture on it.
鱼和熊掌不可兼得
One has to give up on some things.
没理由后悔
There's no reason to be remorseful.
我明白了
I see.
如果你的学生离开，你不会有挫败感吗
Won't you be hurt if one of your students leaves..
去另一个学院？
..to go to another Institute?
如果他不去，最后没考上，我会更伤心
I will be hurt more if he doesn't go and he's not selected.
我们帮助你提高了一些，他们会让你更上一层楼
We fixed some of your weaknesses and they will fix some.
对，你曾经说过，我不是一个人，我不应该紧张
Right. You told me I am not alone. I should not be nervous.
我们将一起攻克难关
We will crack IIT.
我们会一起战斗到最后一刻
We will fight together right up to the last minute.
我是在战斗啊
I am fighting.
你的选择很重要
Your selection is important.
你在哪里考上并不重要
Where you are selected from was never important.
怎么了？
What's the matter?
拜亚哥，从我来这儿的第一天起
Bhaiya, from the first day that I arrived here..
我一直希望我的照片能挂在墙上
..it had been my wish to have my photo put up over here.
-他们也会把你的照片贴出来-不是那边
So, they will put up your photo. - Not over there.
在这里... 你所在的地方
Over here... The place where you are at.
听着，阿琼跟因陀罗学习，他也跟湿婆学习
Look, Arjun learned from Indra. He learned from Shiva too.
但他仍然被称为德罗纳的学生，不是吗？
Still he was known as Dronacharya's student, wasn't he?
难道我不应该在名字前面加上我以前的姓吗？
Don't I put ex-Agarwalite in front of my name?
如果我是你，我会去的
If I were in your shoes I would go.
因为他们能让你提升更多
Because we don't have anything here that they don't have over there.
你和瓦伊巴夫谈过了吗？
Have you spoken to Vaibhav?
没有，我给他打了电话，但没接通
No. I called him but I didn't get through.
我猜他一定在自习室，他会打电话来的
He must be at the Institute, I guess. He will call.
我和乌代谈过了
I spoke to Uday.
瓦伊巴夫的教导主任找他谈话了
Vaibhav's admin had summoned him..
还有其他要去马赫什瓦里的孩子一起
..along with the other kids who are going to Maheshwari.
他要去吗?-不
He is going? - No.
我明白了，所以你才问我有没有跟他谈过
I see. That's why you asked me if I'd spoken to him.
交叉核对？
To cross check?
听着，如果你叫他不要去，他一定不会去的
Listen. He won't go if you tell him not to go.
我为什么不让他去? 如果我是他的话，我会不去吗？
Why should I tell him? Wouldn't I go if I were in his shoes?
这不就是我们参加考试的初衷吗？
Wasn't that the reason we took the exam?
你完全没有准备，他也没有
For which you were not at all prepared and neither was he.
他甚至都不想参加考试
He didn't even want to sit for the exam.
然而整整一个星期，他把一切事情都放下了
Yet all week long he set everything aside..
来帮助你准备考试，对吗？
..to help you prepare for the exam, right?
他本可以回家的，不是吗? 然而他没有回家
He could've gone home, couldn't he? He did not go.
因为他喜欢你，瓦蒂卡
Because he likes you, Vartika.
他喜欢你
He likes you.
如果你不想说，那就让我和他谈吧？
Do you want me to talk to him if you can't talk?
不要
Oh, no.
听着，如果他去马赫什瓦里不是对他有好处吗？
Look, won't it be good for him if he goes to Maheshwari?
-那边什么都有-没有你
They have everything over there. - You aren't.
我这么说不是为了你们的情爱浪漫
Look, I'm not saying this for the sake of your lovey-dovey romance.
我一点也不在乎那个
I couldn't give two hoots about that.
你们俩设定了一个目标
You two had set a goal that you were following.
他自学的效率绝对没有你们一起学习的效率高
By himself he would never study as much as he studies with you.
你在一个星期内完成了11年级的全部教学大纲
You completed the entire syllabus of the 11th grade in one week..
你甚至都开始学习12年级的课程
..and you even started studying for 12th grade.
你以前有没有提前学习过教学大纲? 没有
Did you ever get ahead of the class syllabus before? No.
你并不是你们俩中唯一受益的人
You aren't the only one who will benefit by being together..
他也会从中受益
..he will also benefit.
他知道的，唯一的问题在于他不会告诉你
He knows this. The only problem is that he won't tell you.
那么，你应该告诉他
So, you tell him.
你去帮他，别让他一个人等着
You help him. Don't leave him hanging.
如果你有什么问题，他会来帮助你的，不是吗？
He will come to help you if you ever have a problem, won't he?
拜亚哥说的不对！
Jeetu bhaiya is wrong. Tell me.
你告诉我，他们那边有什么？
You tell me. What do they have over there?
他们那边A3组有80%能考上
80 percent of the A3 batch from Maheshwariis selected, right?
还有20%考不上，拜亚哥没有告诉你吗？
20 percent does not get selected. Jeetu Bhaiya didn't tell you that.
你不按时起床上课，每天我都来叫醒你
You don't wake up on time for classes. I wake you up.
你一个人在那边怎么办？
How will you prepare on your own over there?
拜亚哥没有告诉你，你们讨论过这个吗？
Jeetu Bhaiya didn't tell you that. Did you discuss this?
我们没有聊那么细
He was only discussing with me.
再说我们会保持联系的
Besides, we will stay in touch, Meena.
你为什么这么说？
Why are you saying such things?
真的? 你见过皮尤什吗？
Really? Do you meet Piyush?
他是你学校的朋友，不是吗？
He was your school friend, wasn't he?
告诉我这几个月你有去看过他吗？
Tell me how many times you went to see him in all these months.
一旦你去了那里，你就没有时间联系我了
Once you go there you won't have the time.
还有，你欠我七个泡芙
Also, you owe me seven puffs.
你不给我就不能走
You can't leave until you give it to me.
就这么定了，你不能走
That is final. That is final.
我还在思考这个问题
I am still pondering over it.
我还不知道
I don't know as yet.
迪帕克说一套，拜亚哥又说一套
Deepak is saying something. Bhaiya is saying something else.
-我不知道我该怎么办-看到了吗？
I don't know what I should do. - You see?
看到了吗? 看到了吗？
You see? You see?
我才是那个给你指点迷津的人
I am the one who explains everything to you.
没有我，你就没办法理解
Without me you cannot make sense of things.
你跟他说说，乌代，我也去跟他说
You talk to him, Uday. I'll talk to him too.
你不能去，好吗？
You are not going. Okay?
你告诉他，乌代
You tell him, Uday.
-我能说什么呢?-告诉他不要去
What can I say? - Tell him not to go.
你我说什么对他来说都不重要
What you or I say shouldn't matter to him.
他来这里的目的是考上印度理工学院
He came here to prepare for IIT.
不是吗？
Didn't you?
所以，你去吧
So, do that.
我想现在我们觉得来到了科塔，我们玩得很开心
I guess right now we feel we have come to Kota, we are having fun..
我们一起学习
..we are going out, studying,
创造美好的回忆
memories are being created..
并且建立友谊
..and forming friendships..
但是如果我们在这一切结束时，得不到想要的结果
..but if we don't get the desired result at the end of all this..
那样我们就不会回想起这些时光了
..then we won't feel like turning around and remembering these times.
那么它就会作为不好的记忆，留在我们的脑海里
Then it stays with us as a bad memory.
如果没考上，那些被我们浪费掉的时间就会一直困扰着我们
If we aren't selected then all our mischief will haunt us as mistakes.
我们都是同龄人
We are at such an age.
无法预见未来
We are unable to foresee the future.
你还在犹豫，是吗？
You are in doubt, aren't you?
-和你爸爸谈谈-就好像你很听你爸的话一样
Talk to your dad. - As though you pay heed to your dad.
我不能听从他的指示
I am unable to follow his instructions.
这并不意味着我无视他的看法
It does not mean that I don't pay heed to him.
我做不到
I can't do it.
我无法集中注意力，我不能像你们这样坐6个小时
I am unable to concentrate. I cannot sit up 6 hours like you guys.
我该怎么办？
What should I do?
你告诉我，米纳，我该怎么办？
You tell me, Meena. What should I do?
告诉我，我是应该跳楼还是上吊，或者直接离家出走
Tell me. Shall I leap to death, hang or run away?
我回不去了
I can't even return.
人们会问我发生了什么
People will ask me what happened.
你想考印度理工学院，但是没考上？
You wanted to join IIT. You didn't get selected into IIT?
我看着你的时候觉得很惭愧，米纳
I feel ashamed of myself when I look at you, Meena.
尽管你家境不好，我还是为你的成就而感到羞愧
I feel ashamed of your achievements despite your background.
我什么都有了
I have everything.
尽管拥有了一切，但我却一事无成
Despite having everything I failed to achieve anything.
我什么也做不了
I am unable to do anything.
我父亲是国税局官员
My father is an IRS Officer.
我该怎么跟他说我是废物？
How do I tell him I am worthless?
我考不上印度理工学院
I won't be able to crack the IIT exams.
请原谅我！
Please pardon me!
我该怎么告诉他，米纳？
How do I tell him, Meena?
和你爸爸谈谈
Talk to your dad.
他叫你做什么你就做什么
Do what he tells you to do.
你父母的决定可能是错误的
Your parents' decision could be wrong..
但他们的意图绝不会错
..but their intent is never wrong.
我们要把这个物体从位置 a 带到位置 b
We have to take this object from location A to location B.
对不对？
Correct?
它不会仅仅靠吹气就到那里去
It won't go there just by blowing.
它需要被推动
It needs to be pushed.
这个物体需要一个推力，就像每个人都需要一个推力
This object needs a push like every person needs a push.
所以我们要对它施加力量
So we shall apply force toit.
我们只施加足够的力把它推到中性点
We only apply enough force to push it to the neutral point.
它自身的潜力将带领它走完剩下的路程
Its own potential will take it the rest of the way.
对吗? 关于这个问题我已经告诉你很多了
Correct? I've told you a lot about this problem.
你来解决剩下的问题，然后下节课我们再来讨论
You solve the rest of it and bring it back to the next class.
我们下次什么时候见面？
When will we be meeting next?
我们什么时候见面? 星期四，所以，你有两天时间
When will we meet? On Thursday. So, you have two days.
在那之前，先解决问题
Until then, solve the problem.
坐，坐，怎么了？
Sit. Sit. What is the matter?
你决定了吗？
Have you decided?
这是给你的
This is for you.
给我的？
For me?
谢谢你所做的一切
Thank you for everything.
哇，大手笔！
Oh big spender!
如果你在我身上花了这么多钱，那个考试的女孩叫什么名字？
If you are spending so much on me, what is the name of the exam girl?
你一定花了不少钱在瓦妮莎身上
You must have really splurged on the Vernali.
瓦蒂卡-你同时勾引两个女孩？
Vartika. - You are hitting on two girls simultaneously?
别闹了，拜亚哥
Just drop it, Bhaiya.
来，我给你看样东西
Come. I'll show you something.
过来，过来
Come. Come.
这边
Over here.
你进来怎么不脱鞋，算了，进来吧
You will take off your shoes..? leave it just come in.
你看到这些了吗？
Do you see these?
这是阿玛尼的
This is Armani.
这是古驰的
This is Gucci.
我觉得这个在印度都买不到
I think this one isn't even available in India.
看到那双鞋了吗？
You see those shoes?
LV的
All of them are LV.
这些手表，雷多，劳力士
These watches. Rado. Rolex.
沙鲁克为这个做的广告
Shahrukh does the ad for this one.
我一直想搞清楚这句法语是什么意思
I wonder what's written here in French.
你为什么要炫耀这些，拜亚哥？
Why are you showing off, Bhaiya?
我必须炫耀，这些都是我学生送的礼物
I have to. These are gifts from my students.
这才是我真正的收入
This is my true earning.
我从不穿这些，但我穿起来最好看
I don't wear them but I look best in them.
来自印度理工学院孟买分校的沙布哈姆，然后去了麻省理工学院
Shubham from IIT Bombay. Then MIT.
这是印度理工的阿卡什送的，后来他辍学
This is from Akash. IIT Kanpur. CS dropout.
去了微软
Then Microsoft.
他现在有一家创业公司，天知道他以后还会做什么
He has a startup now. Lord knows what he's going to do.
那是奇拉格送的
That's from Chirag.
这是来自詹维的
This is from Jhanvi.
他们和你一样，都给我送了礼物
Like you, all of them had brought gifts for me.
我都没有接受
I didn't accept.
我不反对礼物，我接受礼物
Nothing against gifts. I do accept gifts..
只要是用你自己的收入买来的就行
..as long as they're bought with your earning..
用你父亲的收入可不算
..not with your father's earning.
努力学习，完成你的学业
Work hard. Complete your studies.
在你成功之后
And after you become successful..
如果你还记得有人叫杰图·拜亚或杰图先生
..if you still remember anyone called Jeetu Bhaiya or Jeetu sir..
那时候你再来给我送一份礼物，我就会接受它
..then you bring me a gift. Then I shall accept it.
我不接受这么便宜的东西
And I don't accept such cheap stuff.
你留着吧
Keep it.
好好保管，好好利用它
Take care of it. Make good use of it..
然后去马赫什瓦里
..and go to Maheshwari.
好吗？
Okay?
是或不是，说点什么，兄弟
Yes or no. Say something, bro.
去吧
Go.
瓦蒂卡没来吗？
Didn't Vartika come?
你没有打电话叫她来吗？
Did you call and ask her to come?
姐妹
Man.
我没法给她打电话
I couldn't get myself to call her.
你能帮我做件事吗? 你能把这些笔记给她吗？
Will you do something for me? Will you please give her these notes?
为什么？
Why?
你不能给她吗？
Can't you give them to her?
天知道我什么时候能见到她-不关我的事
Lord knows when I'll see her. - Not my problem.
你自己给她吧
Give them to her yourself.
还有东西吗?-没有了
Any more bags? - No.
保重
Well, take care.
保持联系
Stay in touch.
我把延长线放在你的包里了
I put the extension cord in your bag.
他要价150卢比，别给他超过100卢比
He is demanding 150 rupees. Don't give him more than 100.
米纳
Meena.
七个洋葱泡芙
Seven onion puffs.
我欠你的，不是吗？
I owed you, didn't I?
我在离开之前要清算一下比分
I am clearing the score before leaving.
-拿着-不，你留着吧
Take it. - No, no. You keep it.
等你到了那边食堂就关门了，吃这个吧
The mess won't be open when you get there. Eat this.
你拒绝吃洋葱泡芙？
You are refusing onion puffs?
我不会放过你的
I am not letting you off the hook.
我在印度理工等你
Meet me at IIT.
到那里再清算
Repay me there.
那边没有卖这个的，所以你得付很高的利息
This won't be available over there, so, you'll have to pay heavy interest.
你得用羊角面包付账-我明白了
You'll have to pay with croissants. - I see.
到时候我会在理工学院帮你解题
When I solve your doubts in IIT..
你得付我双倍的羊角面包
..you will have to pay me with double the number of croissants.
明白了吗?-你能帮我解题吗？
Get it? - You will solve my doubts?
走着瞧-走着瞧
We shall see. - We shall see.
你想赌一把吗?-赌一把
You wanna bet on it? - It's a bet.
-我们保持联系-不不
We shall stay in touch. - No, no.
你好好学习，不要去想这些
You study. Don't think about it.
无论如何，住在一起和偶尔见面
In any case, there's a difference between meeting sometimes..
还是有区别的
..and living together.
说到底，在这条路上，友谊不是必须的
Anyway friendship is not revision that must be done.
专注于你的学业
Focus on your studies.
再见
Bye.
再见，兄弟
See you, bro.
再见
Bye.
请代我向瓦蒂卡说再见
Please say bye to Vartika for me.
双层羊角面包
Double croissants.
瓦伊巴夫！
Vaibhav!
等我一下，兄弟
Stop for a minute, brother.
怎么了? 没事吧？
What's the matter? Is everything okay?
没事，我一路跑过来的
Yes, I ran over.
这就是为什么……-哦
That's why.. - Oh.
我以为你明天早上才走
I thought you were leaving tomorrow morning.
是的，实际上新来的租客让我今天把房间空出来，所以……
Yes. Actually the new PG told me to shift today, so..
哦
Oh.
对不起
Sorry.
我应该给你打电话的
I should have called you.
我没想到你会离开
I didn't think you would leave.
我们很合得来
We clicked well.
- 我们一起学习-是的
With our studies. - Yes.
我是说……
I mean..
其实我也没想到我会去
Actually even I did not think I would go..
但我必须要去了
..but I have to go.
好吧
Yes.
这是给你的
This is for you.
这对你会有所帮助
It will be useful to you.
谢谢你
Thank you.
你冷吗？
Are you cold?
不冷，怎么了？
No. Why? What happened?
你在发抖，所以我才问的
You are shivering. That's why I asked.
是的
Yes.
我不知道，也许吧
I don't know. Maybe.
我想这是因为我有点紧张
I guess it is happening because I am a little nervous.
哦！
Oh!
等等，拿着这个
Wait a minute. Hold this.
-干嘛?-拿着
What's the matter? - Hold it.
张嘴
Have this.
谢谢
Thanks.
剩下的酸奶怎么办？
What will you do with the rest of the yogurt?
别担心，我会把它涂在头发上
Don't worry. I'll apply it on my hair.
恶心死了！
Gross! Yuck!
祝你顺利考上理工学院
Best of luck for IIT.
为了理工学院
For IIT.
再见
See you.
会再见的
You will.
我是瓦伊巴夫
'This is Vaibhav.'
“是的”
'Yes.'
这是我的科塔好吗，存一下吧
'This is my Kota number. Save it.'
“不，不是在马赫什瓦里，我在神童”
'No, not in Maheshwari. Prodigy.'
“我是米纳，神童A5组”
'I am Meena. Prodigy. A5.'
你为什么不早点来科塔
'Why didn't you come to Kota earlier?'
“我们本可以早点成为朋友”
'We would have become friends earlier.'
你好，瓦伊巴夫，你来自伊塔尔西，来到了神童
'Hi. Vaibhav. You're from Itarsi. You have come to Prodigy.'
“你就像阿姨的儿子，对吧? ”
'You are like a son to aunty, right?'
像你这样一个脆弱无助的孩子
'What is the reason a fragile and helpless boy like you..
在学期中途离开家，抛弃一切来到了科塔
..left his home, school and all else mid semester to come to Kota?'
’你迟到了，所以有些落后
'You are lagging behind because you are late..
但你并不孤单
..but you aren't alone.'
“我们将战斗到最后一刻，考上理工学院”
'We will fight right up to the last minute and crack IIT.'
是的
'Yes!'
你有火柴吗？
Do you have a match box?
不，不是为了点烟
No. Not to light a cigarette.
我想点蚊香
I want to light a mosquito coil.
这里有很多蚊子
There are many mosquitoes here.
应该有，我找找看
Yes, I might have one. Let me see.
我可以进来吗？
May I come in?
我是苏什塔，马赫什瓦里，A7组
I am Sushrut. Maheshwari classes. A7.
我住在楼上的房间，昨天搬进来的
I stay in the room upstairs. I moved in yesterday.
你呢？
You?
瓦伊巴夫，马赫什瓦里，A3组
Vaibhav. Maheshwari. A3.
那么，这是你的第一年还是你以前参加过培训班？
So, is this your first year or did you attend coaching before?
我11年级的时候在神童教育
I was in Prodigy in the 11th grade.
-塔尔万迪-哦！
Talwandi. - Oh.
那你一定是个书呆子
Then you must be quite a bookworm.
也不是，我每天也就五六个小时是书呆子
No. The usual five to six hours types.
我才刚来
I have only just come.
每个人都使我大吃一惊
Seeing everyone has shaken me up.
我真希望我是来上11年级的
I wish I had come for the 11th grade.
我觉得12年级有点来不及了
I think 12th grade is a little late.
今年我也要寄宿在这里
I have my boards too this year.
完全不知道该怎么办
I wonder how I will manage.
不要紧张
Don't be tense.
只需21天
Only 21 days.
你只需要勤奋学习21天
You just have to slog for 21 days.
之后你就会习惯了
After that you will blend in.
要来点泡芙吗？
You want some puffs?